CURRICULUM VITAE

JOO YOUNG KIM DEC 16, 2021

PERSONAL INFORMATION:

Work Home

Address: 222 Wangsimni-ro Address: 459-18 Deongneung-ro

Seongdong-gu, SEOUL 04763 Nowon-gu, Seoul 01769

Email: jykim1026@hanyang.ac.kr Citizenship: Republic of Korea

Personal Website: jooyoungkim.info Laboratory Website: suh.hanyang.ac.kr

PhD candidate and Technical Research Personnel in the Biomedical Engineering Department at Hanyang University, South Korea.

I work with Professor In Young Kim in the Smart Ubiquitous Healthcare Lab.

I completed my B.S. in Biomedical Engineering at Hanyang University and can handle most bio-signals and medical images. In particular, I can design the whole systems for electrical bio-signals, including hardware design, firmware coding and analysis.

Through the analysis of bio-signals and medical images, I have become interested in computer science and have a need for related research. So, we created an A.I. team in the lab and I am currently working on this team, doing CNN and RNN based research.

EDUCATION AND PROFESSIONAL APPOINTMENTS

EDUCATION:

2016-Present Ph.D. candidate, Biomedical Engineering, Hanyang University, Seoul, Korea

Supervisor: Dr. In Young Kim

2012-2016 B.Sc. Biomedical Engineering, Hanyang University, Seoul, Korea

Honors, Awards:

2017 Best Paper Award The Korean Society of Medical & Biological Engineering
2015 Dean's Award Graduation Project, Department of Biomedical Engineering,

Hanyang University

The Encouragement Award 7th Capstone Design Fair Final, Hanyang University

RESEARCH

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE:

2016-Present Graduate Research Assistant, A.I. team, Smart Ubiquitous Healthcare Lab.,

Biomedical Engineering, Hanyang University, Seoul, Korea

2015-2016 Undergraduate Research Intern, Hearing team, Smart Ubiquitous Healthcare Lab...

Biomedical Engineering, Hanyang University, Seoul, Korea

2017-Present Research Assistant, Smart Healthcare & Device Research Center,

Samsung Medical Center, Seoul, Korea

MAJOR AREAS OF RESEARCH INTEREST

Machine learning and deep learning in medical data

Biomedical engineering, Computer science, Electrical engineering

PUBLICATIONS:

REFEREED JOURNAL ARTICLES (SCI | SCI-E): * lead author; ^ co-author

- Ro, K.*, <u>Kim, J. Y.*</u>, Park, H., Cho, B.H., Kim, I. Y., Shim, S.B., Choi, I.Y., Yoo, J.C. (2021). Deep-learning framework and computer assisted fatty infiltration analysis for the supraspinatus muscle in MRI. *Scientific Reports*, 11(1), 1-12.
- 2. You, S.*, Cho, B. H., Yook, S. <u>Kim, J. Y.^</u>, Shon, Y. -M, Seo, D. -W., Kim, I. Y. (2020). Unsupervised automatic seizure detection for focal-onset seizures recorded with behind-the-ear EEG using an anomaly-detecting generative adversarial network. *Computer Methods and Programs in Biomedicine*, 193, 105472
- 3. <u>Kim, J. Y.*</u>, Ro, K.*, You, S., Nam, B. R., Yook, S., Park, H. S., ... & Kim, I. Y. (2019). Development of an automatic muscle atrophy measuring algorithm to calculate the ratio of supraspinatus in supraspinous fossa using deep learning. *Computer Methods and Programs in Biomedicine*, 182, 105063.
- 4. <u>Kim, J. Y.*</u>, Nam, K. W., Lee, J. C., Hwang, J. H., Jang, D. P., & Kim, I. Y. (2018). Scalp tapping-based protocol for adjusting the parameters of binaural hearing aids. *Biomedical Signal Processing and Control*, 45, 91-97.
- 5. Kim, D. Y.*, Kwon, J., <u>Kim, J. Y.^</u>, Cha, H. S., Kim, Y. W., Kim, I. Y., & Im, C. H. (2018). New Method for Pure-Tone Audiometry Using Electrooculogram: A Proof-of-Concept Study. *Sensors*, 18(11), 3651.

REFEREED JOURNAL ARTICLES (DOMESTIC): * lead author; ^ co-author

- Kim, J.Y.*, Nam, B.R., Kim, M.S., Choi, J.K., Cho, B.H. & Kim, I. Y. (2021).
 Technical Note: Speaker Identification Algorithm Based on the Deep Learning for Phonetics
 Forensic Purposes using a Cochlear Simulation Spectrum.
 Journal of Science Criminal Investigation, 15(4): 307-311
- Nam, B.R., <u>Kim, J. Y.^</u>, Kim, M.S., Choi, J.K., Cho, B.H. & Kim, I. Y. (2021). Technical Note: Development of Non-contact Deception Detection using Facial Expression and Analysis of Significant Time Period. *Journal of Science Criminal Investigation*, 15(3), 238-243.
- 3. So, S., You, S. M., <u>Kim, J. Y.^</u>, An, H. J., Cho, B. H., Yook, S., & Kim, I. Y. (2018). Development of Age Classification Deep Learning Algorithm Using Korean Speech. *Journal of Biomedical Engineering Research*, 39(2), 63-68.
- 4. <u>Kim, J.*</u>, Lee, S., Kim, K., Cho, K., You, S., So, S., ... & Kim, I. Y. (2017). Development of Bone Metastasis Detection Algorithm on Abdominal Computed Tomography Image using Pixel Wise Fully Convolutional Network. *Journal of Biomedical Engineering Research*, 38(6), 321-329.

PATENTS:

1. NAM, Bo Rum, KIM, In Young, YOOK, Soon Hyun, KIM, Joo Young, YOU, Sung Min, KIM, Yeong Myeong, KIM, Ji Yoon

"Involuntary Emotional Expression Extraction and Quantification Using Facial Landmarks" KR-Application No. 10-2019-0147279

Patent No. 10-2338684

 KIM, In Young, YOOK, Soon Hyun, <u>KIM, Joo Young</u>, YOU, Sung Min, KIM, Yeong Myeong, NAM, Bo Rum, KIM, Ji Yoon
 "DECEPTION DETECTION METHOD USING BIOMETRIC INFORMATION" KR-Application No. 10-2020-0153434

 KIM, In Young, YOOK, Soon Hyun, YOU, Sung Min, <u>KIM, Joo Young</u>, KIM, Yeong Myeong, KIM, Ji Yoon, NAM, Bo Rum "DECEPTION DETECTION METHOD AND APPARATUS USING THERMAL VIDEO" KR-Application No. 10-2019-0140579

KIM, In Young, YOOK, Soon Hyun, <u>KIM, Joo Young</u>, YOU, Sung Min, KIM, Yeong Myeong, NAM, Bo Rum, KIM, Ji Yoon
 "DECEPTION DETECTION METHOD USING BIOMETRIC INFORMATION"
 KR-Application No. 10-2019-0091422

PROJECTS:

 Objective measurement and assessment of rehabilitation for the stroke patient based on the Inertial Measurement Unit and Electromyography Signal Ministry of Science, ICT and Future Planning, Korea (Apr. 2015 ~ Aug. 2015)

 Development of Deep Brain Stimulation Therapeutic Technique for Depression based on micro PET and Fast Scan Cyclic Voltammetry Ministry of Science, ICT and Future Planning, Korea (Mar. 2015 ~ Oct. 2015)

 Development of a system to predict cardiac arrest using complex biosignals Korea Health Industry Development Institute, KHIDI, Korea (Oct. 2015 ~ Apr. 2016, Mar. 2018 ~ Dec. 2018)

 Development of band-typed wearable monitoring device and extraction of biological markers Ministry of Science and ICT, Korea (Apr. 2016 ~ Sep. 2016, Apr. 2017 ~ Sep. 2017)

 Development of personal authentication system based on multi-modal biometrics Ministry of Education, Korea (Aug. 2016 ~ Oct. 2016)

 Development of videofluoroscopic swallowing image-based automatic diagnosis and classification techniques for dysphagia patients
 Ministry of Education, Korea (Nov. 2016 ~ Oct. 2017)

- Low-intensity Focused Ultrasound Based Tactile & Texture Generating Technology Samsung Electronics Co., Ltd., Korea (Jul. 2017 ~ Mar. 2018)
- 전투원 생존성 지표 도출을 위한 다생체신호 계측 및 복합 분석

(Multi-biological signal measurement and complex analysis for deriving combatant survivability indicators)

Agency for Defense Development, ADD, Korea (Oct. 2016 ~ Dec. 2016, Nov. 2017 ~ Dec. 2017)

- Development of Multimodal Brain-Machine Interface SystemBased on User Intent Recognition Ministry of Science, ICT and Future Planning, Korea (Mar. 2017 ~ Feb. 2018)
- 뇌파 기반 상태 판단 로직 개발 (Development of EEG-based state classification logic) HYUNDAI MOBIS CO. LTD., Korea (Aug. 2017 ~ Oct. 2017)
- Construction of multi-modal biometrics and Korean voice database for development of forensic science technique
 Ministry of Science and ICT, Korea (Jun. 2017 ~ Jun. 2022)
- Structuring of Korean medicine classic database for development of korean-western medical diagnostic artificial intelligence assistant Korea Health Industry Development Institute, Korea (Mar. 2018 ~ Dec. 2018)
- Development of biosensing fuction antibiosis wounddressing and instrument for the treatment Korea Evaluation Institute of Industrial Technology, Korea (Mar. 2019 ~ Dec. 2020)
- 멀미 정량화 분석 산학연구(Motion sickness quantification analysis industry-university project) HYUNDAI NGV, Korea (Jul. 2019 ~ Nov. 2019)
- VR 어플리케이션을 위한 안면부 근전도 기반 표정 인식 (Facial EMG-based Facial Expression Recognition for Interactive VR Applications) Samsung Electronics Co., Ltd., Korea (Sep. 2019 ~ Aug. 2020)
- 운전자 스트레스 상태판단 산학연구 (Determination of driver stress industry-university project) Hyundai Mobis, Korea (Dec. 2019 ~ Jun. 2020)
- ISO 21062-2:2018 프로토콜에 따른 바이오넷 혈압계 모듈 BN1 의 임상 평가 (Clinical evaluation of Bionet sphygmomanometer module BN1 according to ISO 21062-2:2018 protocol) 주식회사 바이오넷, Korea (May. 2020 ~ Nov. 2020)

 Development of real-time hemodynamic monitoring technology and prognostic indicators to improve cerebral perfusion during CPR National Research Foundation of Korea, Korea (Jun. 2020 ~ Feb. 2022)

■ Development of Al Technology for Sleep Health Management based on Temporal Rhythm Analysis of Daily-life Brain-bio Signal Ministry of Science, ICT, Korea (Apr. 2021 ~ Dec. 2021)